George and Ira Gershwin Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Financial Documents (Box 112-121)
  - George Gershwin Estate
    - Stock transfer forms, 1939 January (Box-folder 117/27)
    - Taxes, 1937-44 (Box-folder 117/28)
    - Transaction Receipts
      - 1937 (Box-folder 117/29)
      - 1938 (Box-folder 117/30)
      - 1940 (Box-folder 117/31)
  - Rose Gershwin
    - Appraisal of assets and liabilities, 1950, 1970 (Box-folder 119/1)
    - Appraisal of copyrights, 1950-52 (Box-folder 119/2)
    - Appraisal of publishing stock, 1950-51 (Box-folder 119/3)
    - Banking correspondence and documents
      - 1934, 1939-43 (Box-folder 119/4)
      - 1950-59, 1964-71 (Box-folder 119/5)
    - Bank statements
      - 1937 August (Box-folder 120/1)
      - 1937 September (Box-folder 120/2)
      - 1937 October (Box-folder 120/3)
      - 1937 November (Box-folder 120/4)
      - 1937 December (Box-folder 120/5)
      - 1938 January-September (Box-folder 120/6)
      - 1938 October-December (Box-folder 120/7)
      - 1939 January (Box-folder 120/8)
      - 1941 November-December (Box-folder 120/9)
      - 1942 January-April (Box-folder 120/10)
      - 1942 May-September (Box-folder 120/11)
      - 1942 October-December (Box-folder 120/12)
      - 1943 January (Box-folder 120/13)
      - 1943 February (Box-folder 120/14)
      - 1943 March (Box-folder 120/15)
      - 1943 April (Box-folder 120/16)
      - 1943 May. (Box-folder 120/17)
      - 1943 June (Box-folder 120/18)
      - 1943 July (Box-folder 120/19)
      - 1943 August (Box-folder 120/20)
      - 1943 October (Box-folder 120/21)
      - 1943 November (Box-folder 120/22)
      - 1943 December (Box-folder 120/23)
      - 1945 March (Box-folder 120/24)
      - 1945 April (Box-folder 120/25)
      - 1945 May. (Box-folder 120/26)
      - 1945 June (Box-folder 120/27)
      - 1945 July (Box-folder 120/28)
      - 1945 August (Box-folder 120/29)
      - 1945 September (Box-folder 120/30)
      - 1945 October (Box-folder 120/31)
      - 1945 November (Box-folder 120/32)
      - 1945 December (Box-folder 120/33)
      - 1947 (Box-folder 120/34)
    - Financial papers, 1937-70, undated (Box-folder 119/6)
    - Financial statements
      - 1962 (Box-folder 121/1)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 121/2)
      - 1964 June-December (Box-folder 121/3)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 121/4)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 121/5)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 121/6)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 121/7)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 121/8)
      - 1970-71 (Box-folder 121/9)
    - Insurance, 1935-43, undated (Box-folder 119/7)
    - Investment receipts
      - 1940-43 (Box-folder 119/8)
      - 1954-55 (Box-folder 119/9)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 119/10)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 119/11)
      - 1958-59 (Box-folder 119/12)
      - 1962-72 (Box-folder 119/13)
    - Investment statements, 1949-71 (Box-folder 121/10)
    - Investments
      - 1937-43 (Box-folder 119/14)
      - 1950, 1955, 1965, 1971 (Box-folder 119/15)
    - Stock receipts
      - Granberry & Co., 1937-38 (Box-folder 119/16)
      - Guaranty Trust Company of NY, 1940 (Box-folder 119/17)
    - Stock statements, 1937-38 (Box-folder 121/11)
    - Taxes
      - 1937-45 (Box-folder 119/18)
      - 1949-53 (Box-folder 119/19)
      - 1954-61 (Box-folder 119/20)
      - 1963-68 (Box-folder 119/21)
    - Misc. (non Rose or George) statements (various publishers), 1938, 1957, 1968-71 (Box-folder 119/22)
- Legal Documents (Box 122-130)
  The legal documents in the Gershwin collection are organized alphabetically by subject matter and then chronologically.
  - Aarons, Alfred E., 1925 (Box-folder 122/1)
  - The Aeolian [piano] Company, 1925 (Box-folder 122/2)
  - Alexandre, Emmanuel, 1916, 1944-48, undated (Box-folder 122/3)
  - All at sea, 1921 (Box-folder 122/4)
  - An American in Paris (film), 1949-52, 1971 (Box-folder 122/5)
  - ASCAP, 1935, undated (Box-folder 122/6)
  - The Barkleys of Broadway, 1948-49 (Box-folder 122/7)
  - Chappell & Co., Inc., 1935 September 25, October 14, 15, undated (Box-folder 122/8)
  - Columbia Records, 1929 (Box-folder 122/9)
  - Damsel in distress, 1937 (Box-folder 122/10)
  - Delicious, 1930 (Box-folder 122/11)
  - East is West, 1927-31 (Box-folder 122/12)
  - E.R. Squibb & Sons radio broadcast ( 1935 October 31 ), 1935 August 23, 29 (Box-folder 122/13)
  - The firebird of Florence, 1945 January8 (Box-folder 122/14)
  - For goodness sake, 1923 March 31 (Box-folder 122/15)
  - Ford dealers radio broadcast ( 1934 February 25 ), 1934 January 25 (Box-folder 122/16)
  - Funny face, 1927-36 (Box-folder 122/17)
  - Gershwin, Morris, 1898 January 15, Naturalization certificate (Box-folder OV-2/3)
  - Gershwin Publishing Co.
    - 1935 Sep. (Box-folder 122/18)
    - 1935 Sep. 25 (Box-folder 122/19)
    - 1935, 1949, 1970, undated (Box-folder 122/20)
  - George White's scandals, 1920-21 (Box-folder 122/21)
  - Girl crazy, 1931, 1938, 1944 (Box-folder 122/22)
  - The Goldwyn follies, 1936-37 (Box-folder 122/23)
  - Harms-publishing contract, 1923 (Box-folder 122/24)
  - Harms, Inc.
    - 1936 (Box-folder 122/25)
    - 1923 February 8 (Box-folder 122/26)
  - Harms, Inc. & New World Music Corp., 1936 July 16, 17; 1946 November 14, 21 (Box-folder 122/27)
  - Agreement (Ira Gershwin-Harms & New World), 1936 April 2 (Box-folder 122/28)
  - Re: Hollywood contracts, 1936 (Box-folder 122/29)
  - Kraft radio broadcast ( 1935 Sep. 19 ), 1935 Sep. 6 (Box-folder 122/30)
  - La-la Lucille! Your money or your wife, 1919 (Box-folder 123/1)
  - Lady be good, 1924-26, 1940 (Box-folder 123/2)
  - Lady in the dark
    - Limited ed. score, 1941, (Gertie refused to sign) (Box-folder 123/3)
    - 1941 February 20 (Box-folder 123/4)
  - Leo Reisman concert tour, 1934 (Box-folder 123/5)
  - Let 'em eat cake, 1933 July 21 (Box-folder 123/6)
  - Life begins at 8:40, 1934 (Box-folder 123/7)
  - Lyons, Arthur, 1936 (Box-folder 123/8)
  - Miscellaneous agreements, correpondence, etc. 1927-33 (Box-folder 123/9)
  - Miscellaneous memoranda and correspondence (Wattenberg Law Office), 1934-45 (Box-folder 123/10)
  - Morris Gest's midnight whirl, 1919 November 7 (Box-folder 123/11)
  - New World Music Corp.
    - 1927 May 24 (Box-folder 123/12)
    - 1927 June (Box-folder 123/13)
  - Of thee I sing
    - 1931-34 (Box-folder 123/14)
    - 1932 March 18 (Box-folder 123/15)
    - Plagiarism suit, 1932 (Box-folder 123/16)
    - Contract, 1971 December 1 (Box-folder 123/17)
  - Oh, Kay!, 1926-31, 1936, 1944 (Box-folder 123/18)
  - Our Nell Hayseed, 1922 (Box-folder 123/19)
  - Pardon my English, 1932, undated (Box-folder 123/20)
  - Phillip Productions, Inc., 1917 March 15 (Box-folder 123/21)
  - Porgy and Bess-Theatre Guild Archives
    - 1927 (Box-folder 124/1)
    - 1928 (Box-folder 124/2)
    - 1929 (Box-folder 124/3)
    - 1932-34 (Box-folder 124/4)
    - 1935 (Box-folder 124/5)
    - 1936 (Box-folder 124/6)
    - 1937-39 (Box-folder 124/7)
    - 1941 (Box-folder 124/8)
    - 1942 (Box-folder 124/9)
    - 1943-49 (Box-folder 124/10)
    - 1950 January-May 14 (Box-folder 124/11)
    - 1950 May 15-December (Box-folder 124/12)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 124/13)
    - 1952 (Box-folder 124/14)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 124/15)
    - 1954 January-July (Box-folder 124/16)
    - 1954 August-December (Box-folder 124/17)
    - 1955 January-February (Box-folder 124/18)
    - 1955 March-December (Box-folder 124/19)
    - 1956 January-February (Box-folder 124/20)
    - 1956 March-December (Box-folder 124/21)
    - 1957 March-August 26 (Box-folder 125/1)
    - 1957 August 29 [a] (Box-folder 125/2)
    - 1957 August 29 [b] (Box-folder 125/3)
    - 1957 August 29 [c] (Box-folder 125/4)
    - 1957 August 29 [d] (Box-folder 125/5)
    - 1957 August 29-October 30 (Box-folder 125/6)
    - 1957 November 11-December 9 (Box-folder 125/7)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 125/8)
    - 1959 (Box-folder 125/9)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 125/10)
    - 1961 (Box-folder 125/11)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 125/12)
    - undated (Box-folder 125/13)
  - Porgy and Bess
    - 1934, 1935, undated (Box-folder 126/1)
    - 1941-45, 1951-55 (Box-folder 126/2)
    - 1956-63, 1971, undated (Box-folder 126/3)
    - Contracts
      - 1933 October 26 (Box-folder 126/4)
      - 1935 June 28 (Box-folder 126/5)
    - Correspondence, 1934-43 (Box-folder 126/6)
    - Letters of agreement (WBM, GG, IG), 1934 October 16 (Box-folder 126/7)
  - Primrose, 1924 (Box-folder 126/8)
  - RKO (Misc.), 1936 (Box-folder 126/9)
  - Radio show ( 1934 ) (Box-folder 126/10)
  - Rainbow revue, 1923 February 8 (Box-folder 126/11)
  - Real silk [radio] program ( 1934 February 4 ), 1934 January 13 (Box-folder 126/12)
  - Rhapsody in blue, 1929 October 3 (Box-folder 126/13)
  - Rialto ripples, 1917 February 27 (Box-folder 126/14)
  - Rosalie, 1927 (Box-folder 126/15)
  - Shall we dance, 1936-37 (Box-folder 126/16)
  - The shocking Miss Pilgrim, 1945 (Box-folder 126/17)
  - Short story, undated (Box-folder 126/18)
  - Show girl, 1929 (Box-folder 126/19)
  - The song of the flame, 1925 (Box-folder 126/20)
  - Strike up the band, 1927-30 (Box-folder 126/21)
  - Strike up the band (broadcast), 1935 Sep. 3, October 14 (Box-folder 126/22)
  - Swanee, 1921 April 8 (Box-folder 126/23)
  - Sweet little devil: The perfect lady, 1923 (Box-folder 126/24)
  - Symphony Society of New York, 1925 April 17 (Box-folder 126/25)
  - T.B. Harms & Francis Day & Hunter, 1918 February 21 (Box-folder 126/26)
  - Tell me more, 1925, 1943 (Box-folder 126/27)
  - That's a good girl [?], 1928 (Box-folder 126/28)
  - Tip toes, 1925-26, 1937, 1945 (Box-folder 126/29)
  - Treasure girl, 1928 August 21 (Box-folder 126/30)
  - Two little girls in blue, 1921 (Box-folder 126/31)
  - Wattenberg, A.M., 1935-44, undated (Box-folder 126/32)
  - When the armies disband, 1916 (Box-folder 126/33)
  - When you want 'em, 1916 March 1 (Box-folder 126/34)
  - Where do we go from here?, 1943, 1945 (Box-folder 126/35)
  - You, just you, 1917 December 5 (Box-folder 126/36)
  - Ziegfeld follies of 1936, 1935 (Box-folder 126/37)
  - Alexandre Correspondence
    - Aberbach, Jean Joachim, 1944 (Box-folder 127/1)
    - Abrams, Charles, 1937 (Box-folder 127/2)
    - Agay, Denes, 1971 (Box-folder 127/3)
    - American Play Company, Inc., 1953-58 (Box-folder 127/4)
    - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers, 1937-40, 1948-50 (Box-folder 127/5)
    - Art students league of NY, 1937 (Box-folder 127/6)
    - Artists Management Bureau, Inc., 1938 (Box-folder 127/7)
    - Bamberger Broadcasting Service, Inc., 1938 (Box-folder 127/8)
    - Benatzky, Dr. Ralph, 1944 (Box-folder 127/9)
    - Berman, Abraham L., 1938, 1953 (Box-folder 127/10)
    - Bernheim, Max J., 1937 (Box-folder 127/11)
    - Binderman, Mrs. Nathan, 1938 (Box-folder 127/12)
    - Blanc, Ronald L., 1968-71 (Box-folder 127/13)
    - Board of Education, 1954 (Box-folder 127/14)
    - Breen, Robert, 1951-55 (Box-folder 127/15)
    - Brown, Anne, 1946 July 26 (Box-folder 127/16)
    - Buck, Gene, 1937 (Box-folder 127/17)
    - Carnegie, Dale, 1937 (Box-folder 127/18)
    - Chanin Management Corporation, 1938 (Box-folder 127/19)
    - Chappel & Co., Inc., 1937-56, undated (Box-folder 127/20)
    - Colton, Edward E., 1953 (Box-folder 127/21)
    - Columbia Records, 1959 (Box-folder 127/22)
    - Cowles, Chandler, 1952 (Box-folder 127/23)
    - The cyclopedia of American biography, 1937 (Box-folder 127/24)
    - Daily Mirror, 1938 (Box-folder 127/25)
    - The dramatist's guild, 1944 (Box-folder 127/26)
    - Dreyfus, Max, 1961 (Box-folder 127/27)
    - Empire Trust Company, 1938 (Box-folder 127/28)
    - Everyman Opera, 1953-58, 1971 (Box-folder 127/29)
    - Ewen, David, 1956 (Box-folder 127/30)
    - Fisher, Kenneth V., 1942 (Box-folder 127/31)
    - Fleisher, Sidney R., 1937 (Box-folder 127/32)
    - Foote, Cone & Belding, 1955 (Box-folder 127/33)
    - Friends of the Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1966 (Box-folder 127/34)
    - Gelert, Carl R., 1939 (Box-folder 127/35)
    - Gershwin, Arthur, 1937-42, 1969, undated (Box-folder 127/36)
    - Gershwin, Ira
      - 1937 July-December (Box-folder 127/37)
      - 1938 (Box-folder 127/38)
      - 1939-49, 1969-71, undated (Box-folder 127/39)
    - Gershwin, Marc, 1971 May (Box-folder 127/40)
    - Gershwin, Rose, 1934-46, undated (Box-folder 127/41)
    - Gershwin Publishing Corporation, 1937-43, 1949 (Box-folder 127/42)
    - Godmother's League, 1938 (Box-folder 127/43)
    - Godowsky, Frances Gershwin, 1937-42, 1969 (Box-folder 127/44)
    - Gould, Edward J., 1950-53 (Box-folder 127/45)
    - H.G. Harburger Co., 1937-38 (Box-folder 128/1)
    - HJ & MH Behrman (accountants)
      - 1937-44, 1950-53 (Box-folder 128/2)
      - 1954-58, 1968-71, undated (Box-folder 128/3)
    - Hanenfeldt, Zenaide, 1937-38 (Box-folder 128/4)
    - Harms, Inc., 1935-43 (Box-folder 128/5)
    - Hauser, Dr. Emil, 1942 (Box-folder 128/6)
    - Hays, St. John, Abramson & Heilron, 1970 (Box-folder 128/7)
    - Heller, Anatole, 1954 (Box-folder 128/8)
    - Henry Romeike Inc., 1937 (Box-folder 128/9)
    - Hirschmann, I.A., 1937 (Box-folder 128/10)
    - Household Bills, 1938-39 (Box-folder 128/11)
    - Interstate Broadcasting Company, 1938 (Box-folder 128/12)
    - Israel Conservatoire of Music, 1953-54 (Box-folder 128/13)
    - Jedvabniks, Mrs. A., 1942 (Box-folder 128/14)
    - Joshua Orphan Aid, Inc., 1938-42 (Box-folder 128/15)
    - Junior League of Salt Lake City, 1947 (Box-folder 128/16)
    - Kaufman, George S., 1944 (Box-folder 128/17)
    - Kaufmann, Arthur, 1937 (Box-folder 128/18)
    - Koussevitsky, Serge, 1937 (Box-folder 128/19)
    - La Guardia, Fiorello H., 1937 (Box-folder 128/20)
    - Lazar, Irving Paul, 1971 (Box-folder 128/21)
    - Lehman, Gov. & Mrs. Herbert H., 1937 (Box-folder 128/22)
    - Library of Congress, 1952-53 (Box-folder 128/23)
    - Lincoln Warehouse Corporation, 1938 (Box-folder 128/24)
    - Loew's Incorporated, 1953 (Box-folder 128/25)
    - Lyons, Arthur, 1937-43, 1949, undated (Box-folder 128/26)
    - Mailamm, 1938 (Box-folder 128/27)
    - Manhattan, The, 1938 (Box-folder 128/28)
    - Maplewood Theatre, 1942 (Box-folder 128/29)
    - Marc Newman Productions, 1971 (Box-folder 128/30)
    - Maryland Correctional Services, 1969 (Box-folder 128/31)
    - Mayflower Hotel, 1938 (Box-folder 128/32)
    - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures, 1950-54 (Box-folder 128/33)
    - Montgomery, Mary Binney, 1937 (Box-folder 128/34)
    - Mosbacher, Emil, 1937 (Box-folder 128/35)
    - Mueller, Paul, 1937 (Box-folder 128/36)
    - Music Publishers Holding Corporation, 1937-42, 1949-53 (Box-folder 128/37)
    - Music Sales Corporation, 1969 (Box-folder 128/38)
    - Nast, Conde, 1937 (Box-folder 128/39)
    - New World Music Corporation, 1937, 1954-70 (Box-folder 128/40)
    - New York Public Library, The, 1937 (Box-folder 128/41)
    - O'Brien, Driscoll & Raftery, 1937 (Box-folder 128/42)
    - Oliver Cromwell Hotel, 1937-38 (Box-folder 128/43)
    - O'Melveny, Tuller & Myers, 1938 (Box-folder 128/44)
    - Palestine Lighthouse, The, 1938, 1948 (Box-folder 128/45)
    - Philharmonic-Symphony Society of NY, The, 1937-38 (Box-folder 128/46)
    - Planned Publicity Society, 1937 (Box-folder 128/47)
    - Pohul, Robert, 1938 (Box-folder 128/48)
    - Pollack, Mrs. Sidney E., 1937 (Box-folder 128/49)
    - Pollock, Hugo, 1949-71 (Box-folder 129/1)
    - R.C.A. Manufacturing Company, Inc., 1938 (Box-folder 129/2)
    - Radio Corporation of America, 1952-56 (Box-folder 129/3)
    - Revue, 1957 (Box-folder 129/4)
    - Roeder, Martin A., 1953-56 (Box-folder 129/5)
    - Romanelli, Leo, 1943 (Box-folder 129/6)
    - Rosenberg, Sonia, 1938 (Box-folder 129/7)
    - Rosenthal, Abraham, 1937-38 (Box-folder 129/8)
    - Ryskind, Morrie, 194- (Box-folder 129/9)
    - S.H. Riesner Co., Inc., 1937 (Box-folder 129/10)
    - Sam H. Harris Theatrical Enterprises, Inc., 1937-42 (Box-folder 129/11)
    - Saxe, Leonard S., 1949-67 (Box-folder 129/12)
    - Schware, Harold, 1938 (Box-folder 129/13)
    - Scott, Isabel R., 1937 (Box-folder 129/14)
    - Scrapbooks Guild, 1937 (Box-folder 129/15)
    - Select Theatres Corporation, 1937 (Box-folder 129/16)
    - Shubert Theatre, 1938 (Box-folder 129/17)
    - Sirmay, Albert, 1932, 1952 (Box-folder 129/18)
    - Social Security Board, 1938 (Box-folder 129/19)
    - Société des Auteurs & Compositeurs Dramatiques, 1953-58 (Box-folder 129/20)
    - Stadium Concerts Inc., 1937-39 (Box-folder 129/21)
    - Stage and Arena Guild of America, 1955 (Box-folder 129/22)
    - Steinway & Sons, 1937-38 (Box-folder 129/23)
    - Tams-Witmark Music Library, Inc., 1958, 1964-75 (Box-folder 129/24)
    - Theatre Guild, Inc., 1933, 1942-47, 1953 (Box-folder 129/25)
    - U.S.A. Office of War Information, 1944 (Box-folder 129/26)
    - Ulmer, Berne and Gordon, 1942 (Box-folder 129/27)
    - United Jewish Appeal, 1942 (Box-folder 129/28)
    - Van Slyke, Marie Louise, 1938 (Box-folder 129/29)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1938 (Box-folder 129/30)
    - War Department, 1946 (Box-folder 129/31)
    - Warner Bros. Music, 1971 (Box-folder 129/32)
    - Wattenberg & Wattenberg, 1937-38, 1949-55, 1966 (Box-folder 129/33)
    - Weissberger, L. Arnold, 1953 (Box-folder 129/34)
    - Wildberg, John J., 1942-43 (Box-folder 129/35)
    - Unidentified, 1938, undated (Box-folder 129/36)
  - George Gershwin Estate
    - Administrative Documents, 1937 July (Box-folder 130/1)
    - A. Sirmay deposition regarding George Gershwin residency, 1938 May 25 (Box-folder 130/2)
    - E.A. notes re: H. Botkin visit to California, 1937 May-June (Box-folder 130/3)
    - George Gershwin certificate of death, 1937 (Box-folder 130/4)
    - Memoranda and notes, 1937-38, 1949-53, 1970 (Box-folder 130/5)
    - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box-folder 130/6)
    - Receipts and disbursements, 1938 (Box-folder 130/7)
    - EA record of activities, 1937-38 (Box-folder 130/8)
    - R. Gershwin depositions, 1937-38 (Box-folder 130/9)
    - Safe deposit box contents inventory, 1937 July 26 (Box-folder 130/10)
    - T. Berheim deposition regarding George Gershwin residency, 1937 Sep. 13 (Box-folder 130/11)
  - Rose Gershiwn Estate
    - Account of proceedings, 1950 July (Box-folder 130/12)
    - ASCAP residuary membership, 1950 June (Box-folder 130/13)
    - Attorney's affidavit of services, 1952 (Box-folder 130/14)
    - Court papers regarding music taxes, 1955-57 (Box-folder 130/15)
    - Legatees' attorneys, 1950, 1960 (Box-folder 130/16)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1943-70, undated (Box-folder 130/17)
    - Papers relating to R. Gershwin's will, 1948-50, 1960 (Box-folder 130/18)
    - Personal claim of E. Alexandre, 1949 (Box-folder 130/19)
    - Petition by executors, 1953 June 24 (Box-folder 130/20)
    - Will, 1948 November 21 (Box-folder 130/21)
    - Will ammendment documents, 1950 July-August (Box-folder 130/22)
    - Will ammendment documents, 1952-53 (Box-folder 130/23)
- Artifacts
  All artifiacts are listed in alphabetical order and, with the exception of Ira Gershwin's medals, can be viewed in the George and Ira Gershwin exhibit room in the Thomas Jefferson Building.
  - Caviar tin of IG
  - Congressional gold medals of GG and IG (2), 1988
  - Desk of GG, 1933
  - Electric pencil sharpener of IG
  - Fountain pen of IG, ca. 1935
  - Medals of IG (1 Gold; 25 Silver)
  - Metronome of GG, ca. 1910
  - Piano of GG, ca. 1925, Steinway Model B, Serial # 235494
  - Piano chair of GG, ca. 1925
  - Typewriter of IG, ca. 1930
  - Typing table of IG, ca. 1930
- Miscellany (Box 131)
  The miscellaneous materials in the Gershwin collection are organized alphabetically by subject matter.
  - Arnold Shaw re: "Curtain call!" (Box-folder 131/1)
  - Exhibition catalogs (Box-folder 131/2)
    - Exhibition of the George Gershwin collection of modern paintings, The Arts club of Chicago, 1933 November 10 - 25
    - George Gershwin memorial exhibition, The Arts club of Chicago, 1938 March 15 - 28
    - George Gershwin, painter, Marie Harriman gallery, NY, 1937 December 18 - 1938 January 4
  - 2 Flexocol record labels from "Music by Gershwin" radio show, 1934, Labeled in the hand of Ira Gershwin (Box-folder 131/3)
  - "From Bach to Gershwin," 1944 May (Box-folder OV-2/5)
  - George Gershwin lodge newsletter, undated (Box-folder 131/4)
  - George Gershwin mausoleum blue prints (Box-folder OV-5)
  - George Gershwin personalized music manuscript paper, 1 blank leaf (Box-folder OV-2/4)
  - Gershwin: George, the music/Ira, the words., The museum of the city of New York, 1968 May 6 - September 2
    - A catalogue of the exhibition, 2 copies (Box-folder 131/5)
    - Invitation to a reception and preview, 1968 May 5 (Box-folder 131/6)
  - Henry Botkin autobiographical essays (4), 1972-73, Typescript photocopies (Box-folder 131/7)
  - Logbook of orchestral parts, Laid in: IG typescript note (Box-folder 131/8)
  - Merle Armitage collection auction catalog, 1965 May 10 (Box-folder 131/9)
  - News release re: Edward Kilenyi, Sr., 1966 May 23 (Box-folder 131/10)
  - Songs of Adieu [book of poetry], 1923, Inscribed by Ira Gershwin to Benjamin Botkin (Box-folder 131/11)
  - Sound recordings from George Gershwin's library (lists), Laid in: IG holograph and typescript notes (Box-folder 131/12)
  - Works lists, Published songs (Remick); Porgy and Bess publications; Published songs (Harms); Published songs (Music Publishers Holding Corp.); Published songs, photocopied (Box-folder 131/13)